Monte Walsh is what the West was all about.
Monte Walsh is a western film directed by William A. Fraker.
Monte Walsh is an aging cowboy facing the ending days of the Wild West era.
As barbed wire and railways steadily eliminate the need for the cowboy,
Monte and his friends are left with fewer and fewer options.
New work opportunities are available to them, but the
freedom of the open prarie is what they long for.
Eventually, they all must say goodbye to the lives
they knew, and try to make a new start.
Monte Walsh, played by Lee Marvin.
Martine Bernard, played by Jeanne Moreau.
Chet Rollins, played by Jack Palance.
Shorty Austin, played by Mitchell Ryan.
Cal Brennan, played by Jim Davis.
Hal Henderson, played by G. D. Spradlin.
Monte Walsh is a 1970 American Western film
directed by cinematographer William A.
Fraker (his directorial debut) starring Lee
Marvin, Jeanne Moreau and Jack Palance.
The name "Monte Walsh" is taken from the title of a 1963 western novel by Jack
Schaefer, but the film has little to do with the plot of Schaefer's book.
The film was set in Harmony, Arizona.
The story has elements of a tragedy.
The song played over the opening credits is "The Good Times Are Comin' " by
Mama Cass, with music and lyrics by John Barry and Hal David.